David Olivo

"Junior+ Full Stack Web Developer"

CABA, Argentina. (+54) 9 1124016394

E-mail: davidoar15@gmail.com

LinkedIn: David Olivo Rodríguez

Portfolio: https://davidoar15.github.io/Portfolio/ GitHub: Davidoar15

Full Stack Developer with studies in Systems Engineering. I have experience in Front-End and Back-End development, using technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, Express, Sequelize, and PostgreSQL. I possess knowledge in agile methodologies (Scrum), GIT, data structures, algorithms, and frameworks. As an individual, I am committed, responsible, empathetic, resilient, honest, and helpful.

EXPERIENCE:

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER - NESTIFY PLATFORM

February 2024 - March 2024

Intership

Collaborate in the development of the Nestify platform on entrepreneurship and development for potential freelancers, offering courses, bootcamps, mentorship, and benefits for registered and logged-in users, as well as more personalized guidance and profile editing.

- Create a Mentorships Model for MongoDB Database.
- Create GET, POST, PUT and DELETE routes for CRUD operations on Mentorships, using JS, Node.js and Express.
- Collaborate in refactor Routes and Controllers in Backend.
- Be the main responsible for the implementation and flow of Stripe as a payment gateway for the acquisition
 of products / services on the plataform, sending and email to the user's email confirming the purchase
 and its details using Nodemailer, from Frontend to Backend.
- Participate in the design and logic within different React components with JS and SASS.
- Be present in the Daily meetings, report on the tasks completed and showcase demos of the progress made at the end of the week (Scrum methodology).
- Debug code and investigate relevant information to use (APIs, Documentation, etc).

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER - PRODELEVATE

Jule 2023 - August 2023

Professional Practice

Web system designed for product administration, management, and online sales. Its essence lies in providing a robust and efficient platform, aimed at enabling users to create and manage products, carry out sales, control inventory, and offer a seamless shopping experience for customers. I had an active involvement in:

- Model and build the plataform's Database using Sequelize and PostgreSQL.
- Create GET, POST, PUT and Delete routes for CRUD operations on Products, Users, Providers and Categories, using JavaScript, Node.js and Express.
- Implement User Local Authentication from both the Back and Front end using passport.
- Creation of informative plataform components: About Us, Privacy Policy, Terms & Conditions.
- Achieve responsive design.

Presentation: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ohP9JcM9b-8

PROYECTOS:

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER - POKÉMON

June 2023 - Jule 2023

Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp

Design and develop a Single Page Application (SPA) about Pokémon where you can:

- Search for Pokémon.
- View their information.
- Sort them alphabetically or by stadistics.
- Filter them by type or origin.
- Create new Pokémon.

Front - End: JavaScript, HTML, CSS Modules, React, Redux.

Back - End: JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Sequelize, PostgreSQL.

Repository: https://github.com/Davidoar15/PI-Pokemon-by-David-Olivo

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER - DISCORD CLONE

September 2023 - October 2023

Self-taught experience

Design and develop a Discord clone that fulfills its core functionalities.

- · Authentication with Clerk.
- Real-time messaging using Socket.io.
- Deleting and editing messages in real-time for all users.
- 1:1 Conversation and Video Calls between members.
- Sending file attachments as messages using UploadThing.
- Member management (kick, guest/moderator role change).
- Generation of unique invitation links and functional invitation system.
- Infinite loading of messages in batches of 10 with Tanstack-query.
- Creation and customization of servers.
- Good user interface using Tailwind CSS and ShadcnUI.
- · ORM using Prisma.
- Database using PlanetScale.
- Light / Dark mode.

Front - End: Next.js Client, TypeScript, React, Tailwind.

Back - End: Next.js Server, TypeScript, Socket.io, Prisma, MySQL.

Repository: https://github.com/Davidoar15/Discord-Clone

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER - TASK LIST

October 2023

Self-taught experience

Develop a Task List using the MEVN stack where you can:

- Create a new Task, including its title and description.
- View the list of all created tasks.
- Modify a Task.
- Be able to change the status of the task to "Done" or "Pending."
- Delete a Task.

Front - End: TypeScript, HTML, Bootswatch, Vue.

Back - End: TypeScript, Node.js, Express, MongoDB.

Repository: https://github.com/Davidoar15/Learning-Vue2 CRUD-Task-List

TECHNOLOGIES:

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, JAVA, C++.
- Frameworks Tools: React, Vue, Node.js, Express, Sequelize, Next.js.
- Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Prisma, MongoDB.
- Tools: Git, Slack, Discord. Agile: Scrum.

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION:

- Full Stack Web Developer. Henry Bootcamp. 4 months of theorical and practical coursework. 2023.
- 4th Semester of Systems Engineering. Universidad Nacional Abierta, Venezuela. 2021 2023 (Not completed due to migration).

LANGUAGES:

• English B2 – Upper Intermediate: <u>Document</u>